Finding aid for the Alan Mandell papers, 1950-2012 LSC.2123
UCLA Library Special Collections
Alan Mandell papers
1927-2012
1956-2012
UCLA Library Special Collections
Mandell, Alan (Alan J.)
LSC.2123
18.4 Linear Feet (45 document boxes, 1 flat box)
2 Born-digital Carriers (1 optical disc, 1 floppy disk)
Alan Mandell is an accomplished theater and film actor, theater manager, stage director, and producer. He was a founding member of the San Francisco Actor's Workshop and the San Quentin Drama Workshop, managed the Repertory Theatre of Lincoln Center, and was consulting director for the Los Angeles Actors' Theatre and the Los Angeles Theater Center where he ran the Poetry Literary Series. Mandell is considered to be a foremost interpreter and scholar of Samuel Beckett's works. Materials in this collection document Mandell's professional career and include scripts, photographs, some personal materials, and correspondence with many notable literary and theater figures, including Beckett.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
CONTAINS DIGITAL AND AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: This collection contains both processed and unprocessed digital and audiovisual] materials. For information about the access status of the material that you are looking for, refer to the Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note at the series and file levels. All requests to access processed digital and audiovisual materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Alan Mandell, 2012.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9971591113606533
Biography/History
Alan Mandell is an accomplished theater and film actor, theater manager, stage director, and producer. He is considered a foremost interpreter and scholar of Samuel Beckett's works. He was born "Albert" on December 27, 1927 to a Jewish family in Toronto, Canada, but officially changed his name to "Alan" in 1968. After serving as the Artistic Director of Theater '49 in Toronto in the early 1950s, he subsequently spent most of his working life in San Francisco, New York, and Los Angeles.
Mandell became involved with the San Francisco Actor's Workshop in 1954 while visiting his sister, and he helped the group's co-founders Jules Irving and Herbert Blau transform the Actor's Workshop into one of the first full-fledged regional theater companies in the United States. On November 19, 1957, the Workshop put on a historically significant performance of its production of Beckett's Waiting for Godot in San Quentin Prison, which was later discussed in Martin Esslin's influential Theatre of the Absurd (1961). Mandell, as Lucky, struck a chord with the prisoners, and he ended up co-founding the San Quentin Drama Workshop with inmate Rick Cluchey, who would go on to become an actor and playwright. During this period, Mandell also met his future wife, Elizabeth Heller, and the two were married in 1967.
When Irving and Blau were selected to run the Repertory Theatre at Lincoln Center in New York, they asked Mandell to join them in Manhattan as the company's manager. Blau left the Repertory after only a year, but Irving and Mandell remained through 1973. In the mid-1970s, Mandell moved west and joined the Los Angeles Actors' Theatre, which would transform into the Los Angeles Theatre Center in 1985. He served as a consulting director and actor, and he developed and oversaw the Poetry/Literary Series at the Center.
In addition to his time with these four major companies, Mandell worked on a wide range of seminal theatrical and film productions throughout his career, including the 1973 Broadway revival of A Streetcar Named Desire and J.C. Mitchell's 2001 film, Hedwig and the Angry Inch. Both he and Rick Cluchey collaborated directly with Beckett throughout the 1980s and continue to appear in productions of Beckett's plays.
Scope and Content
Materials in this collection document Mandell's professional career and include managerial records, scripts, signed monographs, photographs, clippings, and correspondence with many notable literary and theater figures, including Samuel Beckett. Contents may be of interest to scholars of literature, theater, performance studies, and arts management. The Beckett materials provide an unusually comprehensive portrait of the writer's intentions with respect to staging his work. The theater company records—which include financial documents, grant applications, interoffice communications, press, and programs—provide insight into the process of balancing the practical and artistic goals of running a repertory. The files related to particular theater and film productions not connected to those companies are more commonplace; they consist primarily of contracts, fan-mail, rehearsal photographs, reviews, shooting schedules, and unmarked scripts.
Organization and Arrangement
This collection has been arranged in the following series. Series 1 and 3 are arranged chronologically. Series 2 and 4 are arranged alphabetically. Series 5 is unordered.
Series 1: Personal Materials, 1927-2012 Series 2: Individual Files, 1954-2012 Subseries 2.1: Samuel Beckett, 1954-2012 Subseries 2.2: Other Individuals, 1956-2011 Series 3: Theater Companies, 1954-1991 Subseries 3.1: San Francisco Actor's Workshop, 1954-1988 Subseries 3.2: San Quentin Drama Workshop, 1957-2008 Subseries 3.3: Repertory Theatre of Lincoln Center, 1965-2004 Subseries 3.4: Los Angeles Actors' Theatre and Los Angeles Theatre Center, 1975-2002 Series 4: Subject Files, 1965-2012 Series 5: Audiovisual Materials, 1980-2010
Related Material
Actor's Workshop and Repertory Theatre of Lincoln Center records, 1947-1978 (bulk 1955-1973). Available at New York Public Library for the Performing Arts, Dorothy and Lewis B. Cullman Center. Billy Rose Theatre Division. Record number: b19817948.
- Series 1: Personal Materials, 1927-2012
  Scope and Content
  Contains appointment books, clippings, correspondence, and photographs related to Mandell's family and his early work in the theater.
  - Personal Documents, 1927-1969 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence (1 of 10), 1950s-1960s (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence (2 of 10), 1960-1969 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence (3 of 10), 1960s (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence (4 of 10), 1960s-1980s (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence (5 of 10), 1960-2009 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence (6 of 10), 1968-1983 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence (7 of 10), 1970s-1980s (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence (8 of 10), 1950s-1960s (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence (9 of 10), 1960s-1970s (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence (10 of 10), 1970s (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence - Edwin Booth Reproductions, circa 1980 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence - Opening Night Letters, 1965-2012 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence - Thank You Notes and Facebook Posts, 1982-2007 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence - UCLA, 1973-2012 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Personal Poems, 2011 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Philanthropy - Crossroads School Endowment - Elizabeth Mandell Music Institute, 1992-2005 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Philanthropy - National Play Award, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Philanthropy - Reza Abdoh Wellness Fund, 1995 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Philanthropy - Talk at Thacher School, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Philanthropy - UCLA Elizabeth Heller Mandell Memorial Scholarship, 1999-2007 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Photographs (1 of 9), 1960s (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Photographs (2 of 9), 1960s (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Photographs (3 of 9), 1970s (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Photographs (4 of 9), 1973-1992 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Photographs (5 of 9), 1977 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Photographs (6 of 9), circa 1980 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Photographs (7 of 9), 1981-1993 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Photographs (8 of 9), 1993 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Photographs (9 of 9), circa 1990 (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Photographs - Family, 1950s-1960s (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Photographs - House Landscaping Plans, 1984 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Photographs - House Landscaping Slides, circa 1984 (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Press (1 of 3), 1980-1993 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Press (2 of 3), 1996 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Press (3 of 3), 2008 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Press - Baitz Article and Other Clippings, 1985 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Press - Biographies and Resumes, 1980s (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Press - Programs and Brochures, 1960s (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Travel - Cambodia Photographs, 2006 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Travel - China, 1996 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Travel - Cuba, 2003 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Travel - England Trip, 1967 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Travel - Jakarta Wedding, 1995 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Travel - Mediterranean, 1997 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Travel - Tunisia, Libya, Egypt, 2006 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Travel - Various, 2002 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Appointment Books 1975-2011 (Box 21)
    12 yearly appointment books from the date range 1975-2011.
  - Appointment Books 1994-2011 and Address Book 1965, 1965-2011 (Box 22)
    25 yearly appointment books from the range 1994-2011, including inserted materials. 1 address book from 1965.
  - Architectural Drawing (Oversized), undated (Box 46, Folder 1)
- Series 2: Individual Files, 1950-2012
  Scope and Content Note: Contains correspondence, notes, photographs, press, and published writings relating to individual literary and theater figures.
  - Subseries 2.1: Samuel Beckett, 1967-1988
    Contains twenty-seven handwritten letters from Beckett to Mandell; Mandell's detailed rehearsal notes from productions in which he was directed by Beckett; scripts and monographs annotated by both Beckett and Mandell; and photographs from rehearsals and performances. In addition to the aesthetic value of the letters, these materials have substantial historical value for Beckett biographers and scholars of literature and drama in part because they capture the writer's goals as a director in a range of formats: annotations, correspondence, Mandell's notes, and photographs. As a contrast, a substantial portion of the Beckett materials are from productions with which Beckett himself was not directly involved, including the 2012 production of Waiting for Godot at the Mark Taper Forum in Los Angeles. Monographs were cataloged at the item level and can be found in UCLA Library's Online Catalog.
    - Abbey Theatre, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Alan Mandell Performs Beckett, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Barcelona, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - The Beckett Circle, 1981-1983 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Beckett Directs Beckett - Italy, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - BeckettFest Ventura, 2004 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - The Beckett Project, 1982-1983 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Book Review by John Banville, 2012 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Brienza Interview, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Championing Beckett - Ruby Cohen and Her Legacy with Samuel Beckett, 2012 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Company - Los Angeles Actors' Theatre, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Company - Notes and Criticism, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Company - Reviews, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Company - Schedule, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Company - Text, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Dutchman Rant, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - At Eighty, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Endgame, 1991-2010 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Endgame - Photos and Film, 1980-1991 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Endgame - U.K./Dublin, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Endgame - Visual Press, 1991-1992 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Endgame - Washington, D.C., 1991 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Beckett - Festival, 1999 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Fragments, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - "Friend game" Interview, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Grave, circa 1990 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Happy Days Notes, 1970-1979 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Happy Days Production, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Ill Seen Ill Said, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Inside San Quentin Today, 1961-2001 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Journal of Beckett Studies (Numbers 11 and 12) and Note, 1989 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Letters - Beckett to Mandell (1 of 2), 1981-1984 (Box 14, Folder 15)
      14 postcard letters from Samuel Beckett in Paris to Alan Mandell in Los Angeles. Handwritten and signed ("Sam"). Dated or postmarked as follows.
      1981 November 10 1982 February 6 1982 March 12 1982 March 16 1982 May 3 1982 September 15 1983 March 14 1983 May 9 1983 August 21 1983 December 28 1984 March 8 1984 March 21 1984 April 19 1984 December 13
    - Letters - Beckett to Mandell (2 of 2), 1985-1989 (Box 14, Folder 16)
      13 postcard letters and 1 large envelope (dated 1987 March 19) from Samuel Beckett in Paris to Alan Mandell in Los Angeles and London. Handwritten and signed ("Sam"). Dated or postmarked as follows.
      1985 April 9 1986 June 8 1986 September 12 1986 December 7 1987 February 9 1987 May 21 1987 September 1 (Beckett remarks on Mandell's misdating of his previous letter to Beckett.) 1987 November 28 1988 January 28 (Beckett appears to have misdated this postcard as "29.1.80.") 1988 March [19] 1988 April 14 1988 December 27 1989 July 27
    - Letters - Beckett to Mandell (Photocopies), 1992 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Letters - Beckett to Rosett (Photocopies), 1954-1956 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Letters - James (Jim) Knowlson to Mandell, 1990 February 20 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Letters - Various, 1983-1990 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Leventhal Materials, 1984-2000 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Nobel Prize, 1969-1984 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Notes from Rehearsals for Endgame (London, 1980), 1980-1995 (Box 15, Folder 7)
      Three small notebooks of what appear to be Mandell's detailed handwritten notes about his experience traveling to London and working with Samuel Beckett during rehearsals. Mandell describes the rehearsals and Beckett's instructions in great detail. Folder also includes additional materials.
    - Notes from Rehearsals for Ohio Impromptu and Footfalls, circa 1985 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Photographs - Rehearsals, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Photographs - Rockaby/Ohio Impromptu/Footfalls, 1980-1989 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Programs, 1960-1992 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Reviews, 1982 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Signed Magazine, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Smithsonian Beckett, 1986-1989 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Spain, 1985 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Stirrings Still and Catastrophe, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Texts for Nothing and more, 1997 (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - This Evening, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Various (1 of 2), 1980-2009 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Various (2 of 2), 1988 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Waiting for Godot, 1988 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Waiting for Godot - San Francisco Actor's Workshop, 1966 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Waiting for Godot - Beckett's Notes, 1984 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Waiting for Godot - Coconut Grove Playhouse, 1996 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Waiting for Godot - Contract, 1988 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Waiting for Godot - Fan Mail, 2012 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Waiting for Godot - Lucky Photographs, circa 1988 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Waiting for Godot - Script from Mark Taper Forum Production, 2012 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Waiting for Godot - Paris Video for Beckett Directs Beckett, 1988 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Waiting for Godot - Program and Contacts, 2012 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Waiting for Godot - Reviews, 2012 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Whitelaw, 1981 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Beckett, Samuel. The Collected Works of Samuel Beckett: Molloy. New York: Grove Press, 1970. (Box 17)
    - Beckett, Samuel. The Collected Works of Samuel Beckett: Malone Dies. New York: Grove Press, 1970. (Box 17)
    - Beckett, Samuel. The Collected Works of Samuel Beckett: The Unnamable. New York: Grove Press, 1970. (Box 17)
    - Beckett, Samuel. The Collected Works of Samuel Beckett: Endgame. New York: Grove Press, 1970. (Box 17)
    - Beckett, Samuel. Company. London: John Calder, 1980. (Box 17)
    - Beckett, Samuel. As the story was told. Cambridge, England: The Rampant Lions Press, 1987. (Box 17)
  - Subseries 2.2: Individuals, 1950-2012
    Contains materials by and about a wide range of individuals involved in the theater, the literary arts, and Mandell's life. Includes substantial correspondence with Jules Irving, Herbert Blau, and Rick Cluchey, and minor correspondence with many figures, including Harold Pinter, Lawrence Ferlinghetti, and Gary Snyder.
    - Abdoh, Reza, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Acheson, Jim, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Adams, Jacob (Jack), 2000 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Akalatis, JoAnne, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Akhmadulina, Bella, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Albee, Edward, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Alexander-Willis, Hope, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Allen, Sage, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Alley, Patricia, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Anderson, Doug, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Andrews, John F., 1991 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Angel, Ralph, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Anglim, Philip, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Antone, John, circa 1997 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Appleman, Philip, 1990-1999 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Arabian, Michael, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Arnold, Anna Bing, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Arnold, Frances A. (Macmillan Press), 1988 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Ashbery, John, 1980-1989 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Attenborough, Michael, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Attias, Elaine Mitchell, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Auberjonois Family, 1985-2006 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Auster, Paul, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Bacam Jimmy Santiago, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Baca, Marcello, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Bachardy, Don, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Bailey, Richard, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Baitz, Jon Robin, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Ballo, Robert, 1989-1994 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Baraka, Amiri, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Barber, Edward, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Barry, Jeff, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Beary, Jon, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Bermel, Albert, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Behrens, Deborah, circa 2000 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Berman, Norman L., 1990 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Berner, Fred (Vanya), 2000 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Bernheim, Shirl, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Bhatter, Shashi, circa 1997 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Biber, Michael-John (Fred Myrow), 1985 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Bird, Ann Gee, circa 2000 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Birney, Molly (Poems), 1994 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Blau, Bmanley, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Blau, Herbert (1 of 2), 1956-1991 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Blau, Herbert (2 of 2), 1956-1960 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Blau, Jonathan, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Bloch, Alan, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Bly, Robert, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Boussiron, Xavier, circa 1995 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Boyle, Kay, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Boyle, T. C., 1990 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Bradby, David, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Bradoe, Tom, circa 1991 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Braverman, Kate, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Brenton, David Fox, 1984-1986 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Breslauer, Jan, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Brienza, Susan, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Brotherton, Joseph L., 1998-2000 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Broughton, James, 1987-1991 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Bukowski, Charles, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Bunker, Hank, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Burda, R. W., 1997 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Bushnell, Bill, 1987-1996 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Callahan, Steve, circa 1998 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Callow, Simon, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Cardenal, Ernesto, 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Carey, Macdonald, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Carr, Camilla, 1989-2005 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Cash, Rosalind, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Cayler, Tom, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Chabert, Pierre, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Chaikin, Joe, circa 1990 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Chiara, Judy, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Claiborn, Bunny, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Clifford, John, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Clifton, Lucille, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Cluchey, Louis, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Cluchey, Rick and Nora (1 of 5), 1980-1999 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Cluchey, Rick and Nora (2 of 5), 1980-1999 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Cluchey, Rick and Nora (3 of 5), 1990-1999 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Cluchey, Rick and Nora (4 of 5), 1960-1969 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Cluchey, Rick and Nora (5 of 5), circa 2010 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Cohen, Lynn, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Cohen, Nathan, 1961-1963 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Cole, Patrick (1 of 2), 1990-1999 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Cole, Patrick (2 of 2), 1990-1999 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Coleman, Wanda, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Collins, Mick, 2000-2009 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Cook, Molly Malone, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Copeland, Juanita, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Cortazar, Julio, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Cosson, Steve, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Creeley, Robert, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Cross, A. Donald, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Crutcher, Julie, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Cruz, Victor Hernandez, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Cutrona, Ryan, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Daish, Judy, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Damer Risk, Mary, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Danner, Blythe (Paltrow), 1998 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - DeCarbo, Michael, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - DePina, Manuel, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Desmond, Larry, 1985-1992 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - DeStefano, Lorenzo, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Devine, David, 1981-1985 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Dinkelspiel, Frances, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Dixon, Michael, 1992-1995 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Dodge, Charles, 1984-1985 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Donnenberg, Ben, 1992-2004 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Douglas, Sarah, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Doyle, Brendan, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Dragon, Cat, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Drake, Sylvie, 1991-2000 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Ducrocq, Caroline, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Durand, Paul, 1967-1993 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Eda Young, Barbara, circa 1995 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Edna, Dame, 2008 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Edwards, Ronnie Claire, 1991-1999 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Ehrman, Sidney, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - English, John, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Enriquez, Raul Vincent, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Esslin, Martin, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Fantasia, Louis, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Fehsenfeld, Marty (Samuel Beckett Correspondence), 1992-1995 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Feld, Bruce, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Fenner, Dave, 1995-1998 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence, 1985-1989 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Ferrill, Meghan, 1990-1999 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Fields, Edith, circa 1990 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Fisher, Frances, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Foldy, Peter, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Forche, Carolyn, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Ford, Richard, 1987-1989 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Frame, John, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - France, Richard, 1985-2011 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Francis, Carol Ann, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Franke, David, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Fraser, David, 1990-1995 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Frazier, Kathleen, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Freed, Donald, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Friedman, Alan Foster, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Fuentes, Carlos, 1987-1989 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Fugard, Athol, circa 1995 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Gaddis, William, circa 1995 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Gardner, James, 1979-1985 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - George, George W., 1981-1986 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Georgi, Walter, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 12)